The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
The first 100 steps will be easy
with your Soul Transformation cultivation.
But the final 100 steps to the summit
will depend on your fate.
I call them the Shattered Land of the Celestials.
Shattered Land of the Celestials
Three Black and White Peaks
Heavenly Fate Sect
This cold energy
can infiltrate my body.
In that case,
I just need to shatter it.
Interesting...
This Junior has only cultivated for 700 years.
What did he experience exactly ?
But even so,
with a Middle stage Soul Transformation cultivation,
10 steps
will be your limit.
11 steps ?
Back then, Sun Yun
with a Late stage Soul Transformation cultivation
only climbed 26 steps.
Wang Lin,
how many steps can you climb ?
22 steps !
Wang Lin,
your performance surprised me a lot.
With your Middle stage Soul Transformation cultivation,
this is the limit your Origin Soul can endure.
My domain
is a sliver of comprehension of the Dao of Life and Death.
My Dao is rare
and very hard to make corporeal.
Since I reached Soul Transformation,
I’ve struggled in vain
to try to make it evolve.
But today,
in this Shattered Land of the Celestials,
with the insight of the past 22 steps,
I shall walk 5 steps towards the Dao.
Seek the Dao with the heart,
let the domain enter the body !
Attain...
purity of mind !
27 steps...
This is my limit.
If I go further,
my cultivation will collapse
and my Origin Soul will shatter.
Wang Lin...
Come up to see me.
Years ago, I happened to pass by planet Suzaku
when you were comprehending your domain.
I felt a spark of admiration for your talent.
27 steps...
Wang Lin,
you really didn't disappoint me.
For my whole life, I've always loved 7-colored lights the most.
If you add the black and white of these mountains,
it adds up to 9 colors
to make the most beautiful sight in the world.
Wang Lin,
kneel.
All my life, I believed in heavenly fate.
Today, beneath this 9-colored light,
I accept you as my Seventh Purple Division's disciple.
Wang Lin,
are you willing to become my disciple,
follow the sect rules
focus on cultivation
and complete your Dao ?
As long as Master doesn’t betray me,
I won’t betray you.
As long as the Heavenly Fate Sect doesn’t betray me,
I won’t betray the Heavenly Fate Sect.
This
is disciple Wang Lin’s promise.
Chen Tao
Wang Lin
Now,
I will teach you a forbidden spell.
What kind of spell do you want ?
Master,
disciple wants to learn
a survival spell.
How do you want to survive ?
As long as I have a hint of life,
I would survive
and continue to seek the Dao.
Master doesn't have
such a spell.
Forget it,
I won't ask you to choose
but let you own fate decide.
Asking you
was Master's mistake.
You can't find your fate with a question,
you must stumble upon it.
There are 3600 forbidden spells
behind this door.
Choose the one you prefer.
7-colored Space
Heavenly Fate Sect
The All-Seer didn't lie,
there are really 3600 spells here...
Each avatar corresponds to a forbidden spell.
The Nine Cycle Celestial Refining Tactic,
pure power.
Forbidden spell,
Immortal Demon Body.
Its strength mustn't be underestimated.
A 7-colored spell ?
It can't be weak either...
Unfortunately,
none of these are what I seek.
A gray robe ?
The All-Seer loves 7-colored light
and the 9 colors are supreme for him.
Why is there a gray one ?
This avatar's appearance
seems younger than the current All-Seer.
This gray-robed avatar
is not among the main 3600
but is still bound to this place.
Perhaps this is how
I'll find a survival spell.
This avatar doesn’t move
and doesn't have an aura.
It's too strange...
Rather than guess,
I'll test it directly.
Killing intent !?
Seal !
Are you looking for death ?
This killing intent
is over a hundred times stronger than mine.
Are you
the All-Seer's disciple ?
Exactly.
He very rarely sends anyone here to choose spells.
If he sent you in,
I'm afraid
it was for me !
Senior, what do you mean !?
Life and Death
Reincarnation Cycle !
This domain is impressive...
The All-Seer sent you in here
to test whether I’m willing
to pass the Celestial Slaughter Art to you.
The Celestial Slaughter Art
is an imitation of a celestial spell.
It matches with your
Life and Death Domain.
If you promise me to never leave your enemies alive when using my spell,
I’ll teach it to you.
I won't learn it.
This is a Life Seal formed by the Celestial Slaughter Art.
The more of these seals you have,
the stronger your defense.
They can protect you from death.
This is one of the strongest spells in this 7-colored Space.
Are you sure you don’t want it ?
Why me ?
You’re the 6th person the All-Seer sent here
and I dislike the number 7.
I also made a promise to the All-Seer
that I'd rather not break.
Whether you learn it
is up to you.
The Celestial Slaughter Art,
not bad.
Master, may I ask who
this gray-robed man...
Don’t overthink it.
That was merely Master's second Origin Soul that I forcibly split
during the trials of Illusory Yin and Corporeal Yang.
The Celestial Slaughter Art he cultivates
perfectly matches the survival spell you wished for.
This ring made from purple light
can block the full power of
a Late stage Ascendant cultivator twice.
But you must remember
that if you break the sect rules,
and I'll remove one strike from it.
Break them twice
and this artifact will become useless.
The Second Purple Disciple
had broken the rules once
and used his artifact once.
That's why you were able to kill him.
I'm only giving you this artifact now
so don't make the same mistakes again.
Thank you, Master.
Master,
This disciple wishes to leave the sect to cultivate.
The Heavenly Fate Sect disciples
can only leave the sect as envoys.
Take this token
and go to the country of Lingyue,
a rank 5 cultivation country.
In 3 months,
you must come
to the Eastern Demon Sea.
The Demon Spirit Land will open soon...
Don't be late.
Disciple obeys.
My priority now
is to find a place for slaughter
to cultivate this spell.
Note: There are 5 rank 6 cultivation planets orbiting planet Tian Yun. They are named planet Heaven, planet Earth, planet Human, planet Life and planet Fate.
Country of Lingyue
Planet Earth
It really is the new Seventh Purple Disciple...
We've been waiting
all day for you.
This old man Tian Tai
pays respects to Lord Envoy.
Does this planet
have places where Desolate Beasts gather ?
Countless Desolate Beasts gather
in the Earth Northern Demonic Lands.
Some wild beasts are even as strong as Ascendant cultivators.
But the central area within 300 000 li is forbidden.
Don't enter it lightly.
Even if I'm an envoy,
I won’t interfere in any matters.
You may continue
as you always have.
Earth Northern Demonic Lands
I failed...
How exactly am I supposed
to condense Life Seals ?
Mosquito Beast,
it's yours.
You certainly ate your fill.
Could it be that Soul Formation Desolate Beasts aren’t strong enough ?
Cultivating Life Seal
requires condensing stronger killing intent.
Brilliant Golden Fruits Valley
Earth Northern Demonic Lands
100 Brilliant Golden Fruits !
It's enough to forge a peerless artifact !
Lu Songyi
Elder of the Da Lou Sword Sect
Early stage Soul Transformation
Shi Fang
Elder of the Da Lou Sword Sect
Early stage Soul Transformation
My sect spent years finding these Brilliant Golden Fruits
and sacrificed several Elders in the process !
Qian Qin
Suiyi Sect disciple
Middle stage Core Formation
Since there are 100 fruits,
my sect deserves at least one !
Nonsense !
What belongs to the Da Lou Sword Sect
belong to no one else !
You killed my Senior Brother
and annihilated my sect's squad.
Is this befitting of the great Da Lou Sword Sect !?
Desolate beasts...
Nine Multitude Bugs !
Sword-Sealing Restriction,
activate !
This is bad,
there are too many of them !
This gray energy
is interesting...
According to Tu Si’s memories,
these fruits are formed from a Golden Spirit Root.
A Golden Spirit Root
can nourish a young Ancient God’s body.
Th...
These Brilliant Golden Fruits
belong to the Da Lou Sword Sect !
Exactly !
If you dare to take them,
you're involving our entire sect !
Think carefully about it !
The Da Lou Sword Sect ?
Actually, there’s something
that I'd like to ask you.
"Purity of mind… this child is purifying his mind here! Cultivating immortality, cultivating truth, and cultivating the Dao; it seems this child has gained some enlightenment…. His heart is cold, so no matter how cold something is, it can’t affect his heart. Using this state, he was able to take 22 steps. Wang Lin, Master underestimated you. If you cultivate for more than 10 000 years. I wonder if you can reach the three realms of Nirvana Shattering…"
On the first step, Wang Lin raised his head and his eyes became cold. On the second step, his entire body was as cold as ice. On the third step, the life and death scroll behind him suddenly shrank and floated above his head.
On the fourth step, Wang Lin was filled with energy as the coldness in his heart filled his body. This coldness fused with his domain to create a mysterious force, and with it he took the fifth step!
After this fifth step, Wang Lin’s gaze was like lightning as he looked at the tower on the mountain peak.
The life and death scroll floating above Wang Lin went from being three inches above his head to entering his head and completely fusing with his origin soul.
A domain is something one comprehends when reaching the Soul Formation stage and then one gains understanding of it over the three stages of the Soul Formation stage before it can take physical form. By then, one only needs enough cultivation and celestial jades to refine one’s body from a mortal body to a celestial body. Then, after one’s origin soul completely fuses with their body, they can reach the Soul Transformation stage.
One’s domain will become a completely corporeal existence when they comprehend at it the Soul Transformation stage. However, this process doesn’t happen instantly but gradually over time.
Using this moment, Wang Lin was able to take a important step forward in making his domain corporeal! Although this step didn’t increase his understanding of his domain much or increase his cultivation much, it paved a very important road toward reaching the Ascendant stage.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?